const questions = [
  {
    "questionText": "What is one requirement for becoming a California Notary Public?",
    "options": [
      "1. Be under 18 years of age",
      "2. Have a criminal record",
      "3. Not pass an exam",
      "4. Be a legal resident of California"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Be a legal resident of California"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your jurisdiction will be:",
    "options": [
      "1. The entire state of California",
      "2. The county in which you live",
      "3. The city in which you work",
      "4. The entire United States"
    ],
    "answer": "1. The entire state of California"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A possible penalty for committing perjury is:",
    "options": [
      "1. 2 years in prison",
      "2. 3 years in prison",
      "3. 4 years in prison",
      "4. Any of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Any of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You have how many days to take your oath of office after your commencement date:",
    "options": [
      "1. 6 months",
      "2. 10 days",
      "3. 30 days",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "3. 30 days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you request a new Certificate of Authorization, the State of California must respond within:",
    "options": [
      "1. One month",
      "2. 5 days",
      "3. One year",
      "4. 30 days"
    ],
    "answer": "2. 5 days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The agency of the State that will give you the new certificate is the:",
    "options": [
      "1. Corporation Commissioner",
      "2. Bureau of Notary Publics",
      "3. Secretary of State",
      "4. Department of Real Estate"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Secretary of State"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Using the words notario publico:",
    "options": [
      "1. Is encouraged",
      "2. Is legal in California",
      "3. Is prohibited",
      "4. Indicates lingual ability"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Is prohibited"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a notary willingly and knowingly notarizes a real estate document that they know to be fraudulent, they are guilty of a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Misdemeanor",
      "2. Lis pendes",
      "3. Carpe diem",
      "4. Felony"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Felony"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Death Certificates:",
    "options": [
      "1. Must be notarized",
      "2. Are not notarized",
      "3. Are filed with the IRS",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Are not notarized"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A subscribing witness can bring you a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Quit Claim Deed",
      "2. Grant Deed",
      "3. Mortgage",
      "4. Homestead Declaration"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Homestead Declaration"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The penalty for stating a known false fact as true is now:",
    "options": [
      "1. $750",
      "2. $1,500",
      "3. $10,000",
      "4. $75,000"
    ],
    "answer": "3. $10,000"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Two credible witnesses:",
    "options": [
      "1. Are not allowed",
      "2. Must be over 21",
      "3. Must be fingerprinted",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. None of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When do you officially become a notary?",
    "options": [
      "1. When you pass the exam",
      "2. When the Secretary of State sends your commission",
      "3. When you do your first certificate",
      "4. When your oath and bond are filed"
    ],
    "answer": "4. When your oath and bond are filed"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The notary stamp may be:",
    "options": [
      "1. Triangle",
      "2. Rectangular",
      "3. Only a circle",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Rectangular"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The size of the stamp could be:",
    "options": [
      "1. A 6-foot diameter",
      "2. 1 inch in width by 2 ½ inches in length",
      "3. 2 ½ inches by 6 inches",
      "4. One foot square"
    ],
    "answer": "2. 1 inch in width by 2 ½ inches in length"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you are one of the following concerning a document, you must not notarize it:",
    "options": [
      "1. Agent",
      "2. Employer",
      "3. Lawyer",
      "4. Trustor or Trustee"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Trustor or Trustee"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The fine for overcharging for a non-immigration form is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Up to $10",
      "2. Up to $1,000",
      "3. Up to $75,000",
      "4. Up to $750"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Up to $750"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The fine for failing to notify the State that your stamp or journal was lost is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Up to $10",
      "2. Up to $1,000",
      "3. Up to $1,500",
      "4. Up to $750"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Up to $1,500"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Willful failure to provide a peace officer with a journal when requested is punishable by a civil penalty of up to:",
    "options": [
      "1. $750",
      "2. $1,500",
      "3. $500",
      "4. $2,500"
    ],
    "answer": "4. $2,500"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the fine for failing to post signs in English and in the other language that you use that you are not an attorney and cannot give legal advice:",
    "options": [
      "1. Up to $750 fine",
      "2. Up to $1,500 fine and at least one year suspension of commission and on second time – revocation of commission for life",
      "3. Two – four years in prison",
      "4. $75,000 fine"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Up to $1,500 fine and at least one year suspension of commission and on second time – revocation of commission for life"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a regulation states 30 days it means:",
    "options": [
      "1. Calendar days",
      "2. Business days",
      "3. a & b",
      "4. none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Calendar days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your commission is dated 9/1/05 and you get your oath filed on 9/25/05. Your commission will expire:",
    "options": [
      "1. Immediately – you were too late",
      "2. 8/31/09",
      "3. 9/24/05",
      "4. 9/1/15"
    ],
    "answer": "2. 8/31/09"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The fee for notarizing a circulator’s affidavit is:",
    "options": [
      "1. $0",
      "2. $10.00",
      "3. $5.00",
      "4. Negotiable"
    ],
    "answer": "1. $0"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary can certify a copy of a power of attorney according to the:",
    "options": [
      "1. Civil Code",
      "2. Probate Code",
      "3. Bus. & Prof. Code",
      "4. Notary Public Code"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Probate Code"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You may turn your journal over to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Your Employer",
      "2. No one",
      "3. A Peace Officer with probable cause",
      "4. An Auditor"
    ],
    "answer": "3. A Peace Officer with probable cause"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "During the signature by mark process, how many people write the name of the X signer:",
    "options": [
      "1. At least three",
      "2. Two",
      "3. One",
      "4. None"
    ],
    "answer": "3. One"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you move, you must contact the:",
    "options": [
      "1. Secretary of State",
      "2. Your employer",
      "3. County Clerk",
      "4. Department of Notary Public"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Secretary of State"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you move, you must contact the proper authority within:",
    "options": [
      "1. 1 day",
      "2. 10 days",
      "3. 30 days",
      "4. 6 months"
    ],
    "answer": "3. 30 days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you give up your journal to a proper authority, you must notify the Secretary of State within:",
    "options": [
      "1. 1 day",
      "2. 10 days",
      "3. 30 days",
      "4. 1 month"
    ],
    "answer": "2. 10 days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A commission is valid for ______ years:",
    "options": [
      "1. 1 year",
      "2. 2 years",
      "3. 4 years",
      "4. 12 years"
    ],
    "answer": "3. 4 years"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your 4-year notary bond is worth:",
    "options": [
      "1. $15,000",
      "2. $750",
      "3. $75,000",
      "4. $1,500"
    ],
    "answer": "1. $15,000"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The statute of limitations for making a statement known to be false is:",
    "options": [
      "1. One year",
      "2. Two years",
      "3. Three years",
      "4. Four years"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Four years"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "To be acceptable, ID’s must be current or issued within the past:",
    "options": [
      "1. 1 year",
      "2. 2 years",
      "3. 5 years",
      "4. 10 years"
    ],
    "answer": "3. 5 years"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What does not need to be on a passport?",
    "options": [
      "1. Picture of holder",
      "2. Holder’s signature",
      "3. Notary’s signature",
      "4. Date of issue"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Notary’s signature"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notary certificates are signed by:",
    "options": [
      "1. Notary",
      "2. Secretary of State",
      "3. Client",
      "4. Lender"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Notary"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An ID needs the holder’s:",
    "options": [
      "1. Picture",
      "2. Signature",
      "3. Physical Description",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When taking an oath:",
    "options": [
      "1. Signer must raise right hand",
      "2. Signer must pay extra fee",
      "3. Signer must repeat oath",
      "4. Raising right hand is not required"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Raising right hand is not required"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries must:",
    "options": [
      "1. Keep a photocopy of every document notarized",
      "2. Keep their stamp and journal under their direct control",
      "3. Refuse service to a homeless individual",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Keep their stamp and journal under their direct control"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When you resign a commission, you deliver all your papers to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Secretary of State",
      "2. County Clerk where your current oath is on file",
      "3. Your employer",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. County Clerk where your current oath is on file"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you fail to file the oath and bond on time:",
    "options": [
      "1. Your commission is void",
      "2. You must pay $20 to reapply",
      "3. You must complete a new application",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary seeking reappointment must retake the notary exam:",
    "options": [
      "1. Any time after you have to pay a fine",
      "2. Never",
      "3. Every 4 years",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Every 4 years"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The fine for willful failure to notify the Secretary of State of an address or name change is:",
    "options": [
      "1. $500",
      "2. $750",
      "3. $1,500",
      "4. $15,000"
    ],
    "answer": "1. $500"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries can withhold services:",
    "options": [
      "1. When their employer limits services to transactions related to the employer’s business",
      "2. When a document is incomplete",
      "3. When they believe someone does not understand what they are signing",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which is the true statement?",
    "options": [
      "1. It is the notary’s duty to draft power of attorney, mortgages and deeds when requested",
      "2. A notary does not have to charge a fee",
      "3. Holographic wills must be notarized to be valid",
      "4. Holographic wills are typewritten"
    ],
    "answer": "2. A notary does not have to charge a fee"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary may:",
    "options": [
      "1. Notarize a document in a foreign language",
      "2. Not notarize documents that he or she will sign as corporate officers",
      "3. Notarize relative’s documents",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Signers of the following documents must leave a right thumbprint:",
    "options": [
      "1. Homestead Declaration",
      "2. Power of Attorney",
      "3. Trust Deed for real estate",
      "4. b & c"
    ],
    "answer": "4. b & c"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary is obligated to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Reimburse a surety company for bond funds paid out",
      "2. Determine whether a signer has authority to sign as a corporate officer",
      "3. Let their employer hold their seal if they paid for it",
      "4. Use the all-purpose certificate for a jurat"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Reimburse a surety company for bond funds paid out"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An affirmation is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Jurat",
      "2. Legal equivalent of an oath but has no referral to a Supreme Being",
      "3. Never used",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Legal equivalent of an oath but has no referral to a Supreme Being"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A non-attorney notary (qualified & bonded as an immigration consultant) may charge up to $10 for:",
    "options": [
      "1. Completing a person’s immigration application",
      "2. Oaths and affirmation",
      "3. Per signature on a Jurat",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary may not notarize:",
    "options": [
      "1. When they are the attorney who drafted the papers",
      "2. When they are a real estate agent who sold the property",
      "3. For a spouse",
      "4. When they are a mortgagor in a transaction"
    ],
    "answer": "4. When they are a mortgagor in a transaction"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "For a first-time applicant to get a commission they:",
    "options": [
      "1. Must pass an exam",
      "2. Be fingerprinted",
      "3. Be at least 18 years of age",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A certificate of authorization may be gotten:",
    "options": [
      "1. From the governor’s office",
      "2. From the Department of Real Estate",
      "3. From the Secretary of State",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "3. From the Secretary of State"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Satisfactory evidence of identity means relying on either:",
    "options": [
      "1. ID cards",
      "2. Credible identifying witnesses",
      "3. Business card photos",
      "4. a and b"
    ],
    "answer": "4. a and b"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A California Notary may:",
    "options": [
      "1. Advertise they are immigration consultants",
      "2. Take depositions and affidavits",
      "3. Certify a copy of a foreign birth certificate",
      "4. Normally notarize a will"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Take depositions and affidavits"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An oath is:",
    "options": [
      "1. An affirmation",
      "2. Never used",
      "3. A solemn spoken pledge",
      "4. a and c"
    ],
    "answer": "4. a and c"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A certified copy certifies that the reproduction:",
    "options": [
      "1. Is accurate",
      "2. Is never done",
      "3. Can be charged $30",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Is accurate"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Influencing a notary to perform improperly is a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Moral Turpitude Felony",
      "2. Misdemeanor",
      "3. Felony",
      "4. Infraction"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Misdemeanor"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries shall not perform notary actions if they are:",
    "options": [
      "1. An Attorney",
      "2. An Employee",
      "3. Named as a principal in a financial transaction",
      "4. An Agent"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Named as a principal in a financial transaction"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following is signed in the presence of the notary:",
    "options": [
      "1. Acknowledgment",
      "2. Jurat",
      "3. Certificate",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Jurat"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An acknowledgment certifies that under penalty of perjury:",
    "options": [
      "1. Signer’s identity was satisfactorily proven to notary",
      "2. The signer admits that they signed the document",
      "3. The signer appeared before the notary",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A man inherits a property in Alabama with his sister and they must send an affidavit to the court. He can have a friend notarize his signature and:",
    "options": [
      "1. He can notarize his sister’s signature",
      "2. He can notarize both signatures",
      "3. He can never notarize an Alabama document",
      "4. He can’t do either notarization"
    ],
    "answer": "4. He can’t do either notarization"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries obtain their seals from the:",
    "options": [
      "1. Secretary of State",
      "2. County Clerk",
      "3. Approved vendors or manufacturers",
      "4. Their employer"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Approved vendors or manufacturers"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a subscribing witness brings a document the action is called:",
    "options": [
      "1. Acknowledgment",
      "2. Protest",
      "3. Jurat",
      "4. Proof of Execution"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Proof of Execution"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a principal cannot appear, the document may be brought to the notary by:",
    "options": [
      "1. Any peace officer",
      "2. An agent for the principal",
      "3. A spouse",
      "4. One subscribing witness"
    ],
    "answer": "4. One subscribing witness"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A subscribing witness is placed under oath and asked:",
    "options": [
      "1. Did you sign as a witness?",
      "2. Did the signer acknowledge their signing?",
      "3. Did the signer ask you to get the document notarized?",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An embossed seal impression:",
    "options": [
      "1. Is always required by Notary Law",
      "2. Can never be used",
      "3. Is acceptable but not required",
      "4. Is only for senior notaries"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Is acceptable but not required"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following lists are all Notary Actions:",
    "options": [
      "1. Acknowledgment, Jurat, Copy Certification, Oath, Deposition",
      "2. Jurat, Affirmation, Protest, Power of Attorney, Loan Document Signing",
      "3. Proof of Execution, Protest, Affidavit, Jurat",
      "4. Proof of Execution, Jurat, Oath of Office, Acknowledgment"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Proof of Execution, Jurat, Oath of Office, Acknowledgment"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Credible witnesses:",
    "options": [
      "1. Are never placed under oath",
      "2. Must not have a financial interest in the document",
      "3. Must always know the notary",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Must not have a financial interest in the document"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you resign a position with your employer:",
    "options": [
      "1. You must resign your commission",
      "2. Leave all journals with the employer for the new notary",
      "3. You take the exam again",
      "4. Notify the Secretary of State of any business address change"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Notify the Secretary of State of any business address change"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Military Notary:",
    "options": [
      "1. Is in trouble",
      "2. Charges no fees",
      "3. Can only charge senior officers",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Charges no fees"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A person who is not commissioned and holds herself out as a notary is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Guilty of a felony",
      "2. Legal",
      "3. Guilty of an infraction",
      "4. Guilty of a misdemeanor"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Guilty of a misdemeanor"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An employer of a Notary can:",
    "options": [
      "1. Copy Journal entries of business generated documents in front of the notary",
      "2. Inspect and retain a sequential journal at any time",
      "3. Enter necessary corrections to journal",
      "4. Appoint another employee to use the journal when the notary is absent"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Copy Journal entries of business generated documents in front of the notary"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary must respond to a request for a transaction within ____days.",
    "options": [
      "1. One",
      "2. Two",
      "3. Thirty",
      "4. Fifteen"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Thirty"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The notary or security bond protects the:",
    "options": [
      "1. Notary",
      "2. Public",
      "3. Employer",
      "4. State"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Public"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The only documents that do not require a seal are:",
    "options": [
      "1. Subdivision maps",
      "2. Veterans certificate",
      "3. Circulator’s affidavit",
      "4. Change of venue"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Subdivision maps"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The county named in the Venue is where:",
    "options": [
      "1. The signer personally appeared",
      "2. The notary's business is located",
      "3. Where the signer lives",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "1. The signer personally appeared"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a person has no right thumb and a thumbprint is needed:",
    "options": [
      "1. Use any finger",
      "2. Make a note of this problem",
      "3. You use the left thumb",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If asked to notarize an incomplete document, a notary should:",
    "options": [
      "1. Make a note in the journal",
      "2. Take a thumbprint",
      "3. Charge $10 more",
      "4. Refuse"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Refuse"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Notary seal must:",
    "options": [
      "1. Be photographically reproducible and contain an expiration date",
      "2. Contain the state seal and the words notary public",
      "3. Have a serrated or milled edge border",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The most frequently completed form is:",
    "options": [
      "1. The acknowledgment",
      "2. Jurat",
      "3. Confidential marriage license",
      "4. Protest"
    ],
    "answer": "1. The acknowledgment"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Linda Martinez, a law student, is starting a business as an immigration consultant. She may not advertise:",
    "options": [
      "1. That she is a notary public",
      "2. Her fee",
      "3. Her office hours",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "1. That she is a notary public"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which items must always be put in the journal:",
    "options": [
      "1. Date, time, type of document, fees",
      "2. Date, type of document, fees, address of signer",
      "3. Fees, time, document date, name of signer",
      "4. Date, time, fees, thumbprint"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Date, time, type of document, fees"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Some of the elements of a seal are:",
    "options": [
      "1. State seal and notary’s name",
      "2. Expiration date of commission and county where oath is on file",
      "3. Sequential ID number of manufacturer and notary’s sequential commission number",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary may not advertise",
    "options": [
      "1. Fees to be charged",
      "2. In Spanish",
      "3. The Spanish terms notario publico or notario",
      "4. On a desk plaque"
    ],
    "answer": "3. The Spanish terms notario publico or notario"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The main purpose of a credible identifying witness is to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Substitute for a signer",
      "2. Watch the signer sign the document",
      "3. Prove that a person signed a document",
      "4. Identify a signer"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Identify a signer"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Why are two witnesses for a signature by mark necessary?",
    "options": [
      "1. To view the making or the acknowledging of the mark",
      "2. To identify the signer",
      "3. To sign the journal",
      "4. To sign for a disabled signer"
    ],
    "answer": "1. To view the making or the acknowledging of the mark"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You are notarizing a document for a personal friend. Which of the following must be included in your journal?",
    "options": [
      "1. Signer’s driver’s license number",
      "2. Type of Document",
      "3. Notary fee",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A written request for a photocopy of a journal entry must contain:",
    "options": [
      "1. Type of notarization, type of document and names of parties",
      "2. Type of document, month and year of notarization, and parties’ signatures",
      "3. Type of notarization, month and year of notarization and names of parties",
      "4. Type of document, month and year of notarization and names of parties"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Type of document, month and year of notarization and names of parties"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A right thumbprint is not required in the Notary journal for a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Deed of reconveyance",
      "2. Grant deed",
      "3. Warranty deed",
      "4. Deed of trust"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Deed of reconveyance"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a private employer and an employee enter into an agreement:",
    "options": [
      "1. Fees must go to the employee",
      "2. No fees can be collected",
      "3. The notary must pay for the bond",
      "4. Notary actions can be limited to business transactions"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Notary actions can be limited to business transactions"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An expired California Driver’s License was issued 52 months before presentation to you:",
    "options": [
      "1. It is acceptable as identification",
      "2. Expired licenses are not valid",
      "3. Signer must use a credible witness",
      "4. A subscribing witness could be used"
    ],
    "answer": "1. It is acceptable as identification"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries may not certify a copy of a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Journal entry requested by the Secretary of State",
      "2. Durable power of attorney for health care document",
      "3. Journal entry requested by a member of the public",
      "4. Limited power of attorney document"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Journal entry requested by a member of the public"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a Notary changes a business address to a new county within California:",
    "options": [
      "1. The Notary must notify the Secretary of State of the address change",
      "2. The Notary must file a new oath of office and amendment to the Notary’s bond in the new county before notarizing documents in the new county",
      "3. The Notary must change the name of the county in the Notary’s seal",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A proof of execution may be performed on a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Deed of reconveyance",
      "2. Quitclaim deed",
      "3. Security agreement",
      "4. Deed of trust"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Deed of reconveyance"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary who does not deliver papers to a county clerk after they allow a commission to expire is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Guilty of a felony",
      "2. Guilty of a misdemeanor",
      "3. Guilty of an infraction",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Guilty of a misdemeanor"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A certificate reads: Subscribed & Sworn to before me on August 5, 2007 by ________. Whose name goes on the blank?",
    "options": [
      "1. Notary",
      "2. Signer",
      "3. Credible Witness",
      "4. Secretary of State"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Signer"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You are not automatically disqualified from doing a notarization when you are a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Lessor",
      "2. Vendee",
      "3. Real Estate Agent",
      "4. Grantor"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Real Estate Agent"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "By contract an employee and employer can:",
    "options": [
      "1. Charge $20 for a one person Jurat",
      "2. Notarize outside of California",
      "3. Eliminate their journal",
      "4. Limit services solely to their business"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Limit services solely to their business"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "By using the term notario publico in an advertisement, the Notary’s commission could be:",
    "options": [
      "1. Suspended for a period of not less than six months or revoked immediately",
      "2. Suspended for a period of not less than six months and revoked on the second offense",
      "3. Suspended for a period of not less than one year and revoked on the second offense",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Suspended for a period of not less than one year and revoked on the second offense"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Notary may not charge a fee for notarization on:",
    "options": [
      "1. A power of attorney",
      "2. A circulator’s affidavit",
      "3. A quitclaim deed",
      "4. An affidavit of support"
    ],
    "answer": "2. A circulator’s affidavit"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Notary may use his or her commission:",
    "options": [
      "1. To endorse a product",
      "2. To notarize for veterans",
      "3. To advise clients on immigration matters",
      "4. Both a and c"
    ],
    "answer": "2. To notarize for veterans"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Notary who engages in the unauthorized practice of law may face:",
    "options": [
      "1. Commission denial",
      "2. Commission revocation",
      "3. Commission suspension",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When can your notary commission be suspended and/or revoked?",
    "options": [
      "1. Not paying child support",
      "2. Charging $10 for a set of immigration papers in addition to normal notarization fees",
      "3. Charging a friend less then the general public",
      "4. Entering the amount charged in your journal"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Not paying child support"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a notary is employed by a city, county or state agency, fees collected for non-agency related notarization are:",
    "options": [
      "1. Kept by the Notary",
      "2. Turned over to a supervisor",
      "3. Remitted by the Notary Public to the employing agency",
      "4. Always free"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Remitted by the Notary Public to the employing agency"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "It is allowable for a notary to notarize for a family member when acting as a:",
    "options": [
      "1. Grantor",
      "2. Trustee",
      "3. Lessor",
      "4. Employee"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Employee"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A notary can notarize documents to be filed in another State but:",
    "options": [
      "1. Must use California form",
      "2. Can’t certify signer holds a particular capacity",
      "3. Can’t charge any fees",
      "4. Only jurats"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Can’t certify signer holds a particular capacity"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An oath to a witness:",
    "options": [
      "1. Always refers to God",
      "2. Can use phrase “under penalty of perjury”",
      "3. Never refers to a Superior Being",
      "4. Has only one recommended question"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Can use phrase “under penalty of perjury”"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your employer, John Smith, asks to see your journal, which you use in business, to see who is giving him the most business, you should:",
    "options": [
      "1. Let him look at your journal",
      "2. Refuse to let him look at the journal",
      "3. Let him see only the items pertaining to his business",
      "4. Remind him it is your journal and he may not look at it"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Let him see only the items pertaining to his business"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "In the case of the death of a notary public, the personal representative of the deceased shall:",
    "options": [
      "1. Promptly notify the Secretary of State and return journal to the Secretary of State",
      "2. Promptly notify the Secretary of State and return seal and journal to the State",
      "3. Promptly notify the County where the oath and bond are recorded",
      "4. Promptly notify the Secretary of State and send their papers and records to the county where their oath is recorded."
    ],
    "answer": "4. Promptly notify the Secretary of State and send their papers and records to the county where their oath is recorded."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "No fees may be charged for verifying:",
    "options": [
      "1. A jurat",
      "2. Nomination document or circulator’s affidavit",
      "3. Any acknowledgments",
      "4. Any protests"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Nomination document or circulator’s affidavit"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When performing a signature by mark notarization:",
    "options": [
      "1. The signer must make his or her mark in the Notary’s journal",
      "2. The signer does not have to be identified",
      "3. The notary must make the mark in his or her journal",
      "4. The notary must sign the person’s name near his or her mark on the signature line"
    ],
    "answer": "1. The signer must make his or her mark in the Notary’s journal"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A Notary Public can notarize a signature on a document that:",
    "options": [
      "1. They signed as a principal",
      "2. In which they have a direct financial interest",
      "3. Is incomplete",
      "4. Is in a foreign language"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Is in a foreign language"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following must be included in a Journal:",
    "options": [
      "1. Date of document",
      "2. Address of signer",
      "3. Character of every document",
      "4. Thumbprint of a trustee deed’s signer"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Character of every document"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a credible witness personally knows the signer and the notary:",
    "options": [
      "1. Only one witness is needed",
      "2. Two witnesses are needed",
      "3. Three witnesses are needed",
      "4. None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Only one witness is needed"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When the last day for filing an instrument or other document with a state agency falls upon a Saturday or holiday, such act may be performed:",
    "options": [
      "1. Within one week",
      "2. Within two weeks",
      "3. Within thirty days",
      "4. Upon the next business day"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Upon the next business day"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Notaries need not record in their journals:",
    "options": [
      "1. The date and time of notarization",
      "2. The fees charged for a notarial services",
      "3. Type of document notarized",
      "4. The signer’s address"
    ],
    "answer": "4. The signer’s address"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When the venue of the Notary’s certificate has been filled in beforehand with an incorrect state and county, the Notary must:",
    "options": [
      "1. Attach a loose certificate with a correct venue",
      "2. Reject the document",
      "3. Not tamper with words that may have been filled in by an attorney",
      "4. Line through the inapplicable words, writing in the correct state and county"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Line through the inapplicable words, writing in the correct state and county"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Any person who coerces a notary to perform improperly is guilty of:",
    "options": [
      "1. A Felony",
      "2. An Infraction",
      "3. Nothing",
      "4. Misdemeanor"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Misdemeanor"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Effective July 1, 2005 all appointed persons must complete:",
    "options": [
      "1. Six hours of study",
      "2. Three hours of study",
      "3. Forty-five hours of study",
      "4. A 60 question exam"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Six hours of study"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The main purpose of an acknowledgment is to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Authenticate signatures",
      "2. Establish mental competence",
      "3. Require personal appearance",
      "4. Both a and c"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Both a and c"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When notarizing a document containing an acknowledgment, the Notary:",
    "options": [
      "1. Must see the document signer sign before them",
      "2. May accept a document that has already been signed",
      "3. Must administer an oath",
      "4. Must take a copy of the acknowledgment"
    ],
    "answer": "2. May accept a document that has already been signed"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "To communicate with the Secretary of State about a change in address:",
    "options": [
      "1. A Notary must communicate the change when it is a business address",
      "2. A Notary must communicate the change when it is a residence address",
      "3. By certified mail within 30 days",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When is an oath involved with an acknowledgment:",
    "options": [
      "1. Every time",
      "2. When the signer would like to swear that the contents of the document are true",
      "3. When the signer utilizes a credible witness as ID",
      "4. An oath is never used in an acknowledgment"
    ],
    "answer": "4. An oath is never used in an acknowledgment"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "One main purpose of a Jurat is to:",
    "options": [
      "1. Not identify the signer",
      "2. Copy certify a form",
      "3. Make sure the signer signs in front of the Notary",
      "4. Gain evidence to insure truthfulness"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Make sure the signer signs in front of the Notary"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "To establish proper ID the Notary must accept which of the following from the principal:",
    "options": [
      "1. Two credible witnesses with ID’s who personally know the principal",
      "2. Credible witness personally known by Notary and principal with proper ID.",
      "3. One proper ID – current or issued in the last five years",
      "4. All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "4. All of the above"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Exceptions to personal appearance by the principal are:",
    "options": [
      "1. There are none",
      "2. Credible witness",
      "3. Photo Business Card",
      "4. Subscribing Witness"
    ],
    "answer": "4. Subscribing Witness"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A foreign passport must have one additional item:",
    "options": [
      "1. Stamp from U.S. Immigration Agency",
      "2. Address of signer",
      "3. Phone number of Issuing County",
      "4. Thumbprint"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Stamp from U.S. Immigration Agency"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "To meet the 30 calendar day filing limit of the oath with the county you must:",
    "options": [
      "1. Get them postmarked by 30 days",
      "2. Keep them until you can hand deliver them",
      "3. Allow for any form of delay",
      "4. Pay a fee if late"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Get them postmarked by 30 days"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A judgment is lodged against a Notary for $22,000 and the bonding company pays $15,000 to the client. The notary is liable for:",
    "options": [
      "1. $7,000",
      "2. $22,000",
      "3. $15,000",
      "4. $0"
    ],
    "answer": "1. $7,000"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The key wording of an acknowledgement is:",
    "options": [
      "1. Subscribed and sworn to",
      "2. I swear the document is true",
      "3. Personally appeared",
      "4. Protest the payment"
    ],
    "answer": "3. Personally appeared"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A subscribing witness can be identified by:",
    "options": [
      "1. Their current U.S. Passport",
      "2. One credible witness known to the subscribing witness and the notary who has ID",
      "3. Two credible witnesses with proper ID cards",
      "4. A principal who knows them personally"
    ],
    "answer": "2. One credible witness known to the subscribing witness and the notary who has ID"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The true statement below about qualifications is, you must be:",
    "options": [
      "1. Able to read Spanish",
      "2. A U.S. Citizen",
      "3. 18 years of age",
      "4. Resident of California"
    ],
    "answer": "3. 18 years of age"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "It is never acceptable to affix a notary seal and signature to a document without:",
    "options": [
      "1. The notarial wording",
      "2. Being paid",
      "3. Giving an oath",
      "4. Seeing the person sign the document"
    ],
    "answer": "1. The notarial wording"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If a notary is unable to communicate with a customer the notary:",
    "options": [
      "1. Should use an interpreter",
      "2. Refer them to someone who speaks their language",
      "3. Report them to Immigration authorities",
      "4. Should notarize any regular documents"
    ],
    "answer": "2. Refer them to someone who speaks their language"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "In foreign language advertising regulations there are strict rules but the one exception is:",
    "options": [
      "1. A business card in the foreign language",
      "2. A single desk plaque",
      "3. An 8 ½” x 11” brochure",
      "4. Yellow pages advertising"
    ],
    "answer": "2. A single desk plaque"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a public agency pays an employee’s expenses, the fees:",
    "options": [
      "1. Shall be remitted to the agency",
      "2. Are distributed per an employee-agency agreement",
      "3. Are never collected",
      "4. Go to the notary"
    ],
    "answer": "1. Shall be remitted to the agency"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When a check has not been honored for payment, the Secretary of State shall give a written notice. If no correction is done a second notice of cancellation shall be effective when:",
    "options": [
      "1. 90 days",
      "2. 30 days",
      "3. 20 days",
      "4. 10 days"
    ],
    "answer": "4. 10 days"
  },
  ];
  
  export default questions;